Guide to the Richard White papers SC1323
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Books
  - The Roots of Dependency: Subsistence, Environment, and Social Change Among the Choctaws, Pawnees, and Navajos.
    - Navajo Politics - Morgan, Palmer opposition, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - Spicer - Collier (Box 31, Folder 43)
    - Archeology, 1882 (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Rodent control, 1907-1939 (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - Navajo Relief, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - Statistics- Stockraising, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 47)
    - Nav. Attitudes - stock + reduction, 1934-1973 (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - Youngblood - Nav. Trading (Box 31, Folder 49)
    - Nav. Council - Reorganization, 1936-1937 (Box 31, Folder 50)
    - Gazing Cases - Prosecution, 1935-1940 (Box 31, Folder 51)
    - NYB - Stock Reduction (Box 31, Folder 52)
    - Burton - As problems, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 53)
    - Grazing Regulations, 1935-1941 (Box 31, Folder 54)
    - "Nav. Indian Problem" Phelps - Stoke Fund, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 55)
    - Herding practices - dipping et., 1907-1939 (Box 31, Folder 56)
    - Hill Report Ethnology - Future te. (Box 31, Folder 57)
    - McGiunes Report - from survey + related reports, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 58)
    - SCS - Navajo Project outlines (Box 31, Folder 59)
    - 2 ch reports, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 60)
    - Tribal Council (D of I library), 1935 Nov (Box 31, Folder 61)
    - Tribal Council meetings (Box 31, Folder 62)
    - Manuscript Collections summer trip, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 63)
    - Summary Reports - reduction + genl. Conditions, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 64)
    - Rationales + justifications plans for reductios (Box 31, Folder 65)
    - Edmondson, William D. Visiting faculty applicant, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 66)
- Other publications and articles
  - Teal-Maps, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edited Version: Although Ian, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - final draft N. A History, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gold Russ, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NPS paper, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foner Essay, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ahanagran, Chapter 1-8, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Turher for Martin, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Final draft Self- although I am dead, 1894 Aug (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Although I am Dead Ultimate Final Copy, 1996 Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Western history, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Current Weirdness, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dictionary of American Culture, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Final Draft: Fictions, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Textbook Article, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Other Wests Proof, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Neb. Intro, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ostler/Johnson, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - NPS article, 1994 Aug (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Native American Studies, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Harpers Reject, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - SIMS, H., undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Natures Nation, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Notes: Textbook article, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Heritage Interview, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Galley - Work and Nature, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Are you an Environmentalist, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Final Draft- Williamsburg article, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Pontiac, 1994 Jun 24 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Progress Final Draft, 1994 Aug (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Indian Peoples + The Material World, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Other Wests (Draft), undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Seattle Sun, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - William + Mary Quarterly Shammas Proofs, 1994 Sep 1 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Final Draft: Fictions of Patriarchy, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - What Chigabe Knew, 1994 Oct (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Final Draft Progress, 1992 Aug (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - AH - Columbus draft, 1991 Dec (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Drafts Comment Self, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Progress, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Animals + Enterprise First Version, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "The Frontier in American Culture" Press Coverage, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - handwritten notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Turner, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Raee Relations Article Draft, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Columbian Consequences Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Drafts Discovery, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Discovery, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - JAH articles, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Discovery draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Discovery draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Smithsonian Article- handouts, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Carstensen Entry Encyclopedia of American West, 1994 Sep (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Final proofs BB + Tarner, 1994 May (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Comparison to American thought, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Animals + Enterprise: Final Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Columbia Consequences, 1991 Jan (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Work + Nature, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Teaching Article, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Utah State University correspondence, 1990 Nov (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Animals + Enterprise - Final Draft, 1991 Jan (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Discovery, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Tarner - article - notes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Reading for Discovery article also Pros. Article, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Discovery - representations, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Discovery - Columbus, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Discovery - Notes on books, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Novel (Box 35, Folder 1)
- Audiovisual Materials
  - History of Nature Marsh: Dominion over Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - History of Nature Carson: Kinship with Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - Newberry Library Exhibit Video Initial A-B Roll Assembly, 1994 May 4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - History of Nature Thoreau: Transcending Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - The Homestead/rough cut, 1997 Nov 14; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - History of Nature Aristotle: the Soul of Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - History of Nature Darwin: the Indifference of Nature, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - A Continent Transformed Promo Reel, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 39)
  - White #3 Chapter 8, 9, 10, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Columbia River as of (back-up) Col 1, Col 2a, Col3, Col4, 1994 Aug 15; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Smith rewrite, Toronto rewrite, Smeak, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Dr. S 7.72 Dos Disk grad student Tanner pt. 2, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Aunie Dillard Rival Empires, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Boston Talk Exploring the Pacific Ross Frank, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1990; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Misc. - Worel McKinley Nash, Opie Ball, Thahn, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Welch West 3 Word 5.0 Labels Indgrad, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Dr S 7.72 Dos Disk 1/4 Rees + Revival Wash, Merse, Sellara, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Col 3. doc is the unrevised version, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Nature's nation 3b Talk notes, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - NN 3b Tanner Lecture 2, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Backup 2 750K empl. Not formatted, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Reviews 4, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Corr. 3, 1990; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Report - Letters Syllabus - Nature Richard White, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - West History Environmental History Reading Lists books for RR. Stanf. Grad Indians, Nature, HstAA512, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Misfortune Rewrites, 2000 Apr; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Corr., 1990; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Col. IF (for final copy) Col 4, 1994 Oct 7; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - HSTAA501 syllabus for 1996 syl 96 - Doc (word) for Richard White, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Col 3 pontiac Col. 4, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - NN3 (1-32) infected disk, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - White disk #1 of 1 microsoft Word 6 - PC misfortune copy, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - correspondence letters diss. Chapters Dr. Levine, Stanford post doc syllabi, 1998 Jun 10; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Hst. 201, Hst 501, Hst. 513 Natures nation survey New Republic, Talles, 1998 Jun 10; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - railroad notes, railroad sources, phrenology, Hst. 498, papers, 1998 Jun 10; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - New Republic North America Campbell Diaries Transnational natures, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Dr S 7.72 Win95 Disk 2/4 Maps, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Articles, book review from office, my documents, 1998 Jun 10; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Final Col 3F, 1994 Oct; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Windows: references West for Faner, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Richard White CV White UT Rival Empires, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Cooke Papers, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - OM Footnotes: 4 chaps. Col 1a doc, Col 1ab.doc, Col2d.doc, - Col 4bc.doc, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - DrS 7.72 Magic Bullet NW 1-2, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - unlabeled, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - NN, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Mwave Disk 1, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - RJ SYL96 - Doc (HSTAA 501), 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Culture: WHA Onashex Thornton misc. Rees, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Radius Emerson others, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Early rewrites Disney sources - Interviews RR sources, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - LRB 2 (Little River Ottaves) WP. 6.1, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Tanner Lecture OAH, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - PC First Class Eastern Report draft recs, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Dr S 7.72 Win95 disk 3/4 Natures, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Grad files etc. (misc.) expendable, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Tanner lecture Whito R Tax Richard White, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Dr S 7.72 Dos Disk 4/4 Paul Johnson letter McMurtry etc. Tanner 2, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Corr. 2 Jenkins, 1990; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)
  - Col 4, 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 39)